David Valles

San Jose, CA (408) 375-7704 davidtivalles@gmail.com dtjv.io github.com/dtjv

I am a software developer, experienced building, testing and deploying React-based web applications, writing articles from my experiences and collaborating with clientele. Passionate about intuitive UI/UX, writing maintainable code and helping people and organizations reach their goals. I enjoy the gamut of full-stack web technologies and I'm excited to keep learning and building.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer - Freelance

2017-2020

BMI Fitness | docs | website

- Developed a fitness studio website to present services, staff bios, and published content and to capture customer leads.
- Built with Jekyll, Materialize and Sass. Integrated Formspree.io for form routing and Forestry.io for content management.

Web Developer - Freelance

2020

Richard Gullion | docs | website

Created a website to showcase Rich's artwork. Built using Gatsby for image optimization and styled using Tailwind CSS.

Software Developer - Freelance

2015-2017

Club One Fitness

- Created a Node is CLI to bundle client workout files (in Markdown) into one, printable web page. (docs)
- Built an app for trainers to collect client FMS screening data. Used jQuery, Firebase and Google Auth. (docs)

Personal Trainer 2005-2020

Club One Fitness / Forma Gym / Realm Fitness

- Developed safe and appropriate strength training, weight loss and sports conditioning programs for clientele.
- Consistently ranked as top trainer in sales and client retention resulting in a referral-only based business.

PROJECTS

Terra | docs | demo

- Developed a full-stack, scheduling app for a garden center's delivery service. Built with Typescript, Next.js, and MongoDB.
- Provides an intuitive form-wizard using Chakra-UI for accurate data entry. Calculates delivery times via Google Maps API
 to maximize driver time. Includes a familiar drag-n-drop feature using React-Dnd to maintain schedule integrity.

Memowise | docs | demo

Created a full-stack, Next.js and MongoDB education web app offering algorithm-based study, dynamic quizzes, and
personalized public and private flashcards sets. Sign-in via GitHub for personalized features. Styled using Tailwind CSS.

Maximus | docs | demo

Built a responsive React web app to create workouts and visualize them in an interactive bar chart using Chart.js.

Travel Salem | docs | demo

• Designed a UI concept for a travel site, with a focus on an intuitive site navigation, surfacing buried content and improving page load performance. Built using Next.is and Tailwind CSS.

EDUCATION

Cal Poly, San Luis Obispo

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

INTERESTS

Cycling in SLO, Formula 1, Philz Coffee, chunky peanut butter, calisthenics, minimalist architecture and being in Nature.